David Lasso

Profile

Tenacious individual, focused and self-motivated, with a clear, logical mind and a practical approach to problem solving I have developed effective, personable communication skills through client handling experiences in IT and previous roles. Enjoys being a team player and using own initiative and works well under pressure. With a positive, resilient outlook and a willingness to learn new skills, makes for a confident high achiever looking to excel.

I have been collaborating IT skills for over 20 years and fell into the IT world as I found it uncomplicated to get to grips with IT terms. I mainly worked with operating systems, devices and IT infrastructures, I admit while the learning curve was a forgiving and exciting climb, I always felt there was something missing or different to learn and was not sure what it was.

In my current role I was given the opportunity to head down a new avenue and found a new love for programming and here is where I would like to continue my path and develop it further.

Employment History

Sys administrator/Dev-Ops, Touchdown Holidays

23/05/16 - Present

- I was the sole IT support for the UK sites, 1st 3rd link. Remote as well as face to face, creating and maintaining user accounts.
- Server side support for UK sites, from installation to maintenance.
- Supporting and maintaining the IP telephone system.
- Creating bespoke sales reports, company trends on products reports, using postgresql, python and pandas.
- Liaised with UK staff and US developers in our mother company in the Austin, Texas USA, with any issues on our uk website or internal CMS system.
- I was developing an internal website using Flask to show sales data and trends.
- Fully managed the relocation to a new site, of all IT and Telephonic facilities, this happed twice.
- Fully managed the relocation of all users from office based to home workers and supported this 24/7
- All python, pandas, Flask, postgresql, git, html, css and django was all self direct learning and was supported by the company.

IT Recruitment Account Manager, C&M Travel Recruitment 26/01/15 – 20/04/16

- Business Development contacting existing clients and making new clients.
- Provide a high quality recruitment consulting service to the client to find out their needs
 for IT vacancies they may have or may have in mind and provide them with the right
 information to make the right choice in candidates.
- Keeping a well organised daily, weekly and monthly schedule to aid achieving KPIs.
- Creating and organising candidate database.
- Sourcing candidates for existing vacancies, sourcing candidates for speculative CVs for
- Screening and interviewing candidates for existing vacancies and for candidate database
- Ad writing for client vacancies and creating mailshots to clients or candidate to generate business.

IT Technician, The London Oratory School

23/04/07 - 23/01/15

• I built a positive long term business relationships with both internal and external, colleagues and suppliers by demonstrating a supportive, informative and cooperative attitude, offering help and advice, communicating positively and constructively and showing concern for their needs whilst being responsive to their requests

- Compelled to hit daily targets and achieving them with a high level of service.
- Solid understanding of most Microsoft products, these included MS Server 2000 -12, MS Exchange, MS SQL and MS Office 2003 – 365
- Migrated the school from and old OS to a new OS over the summer break which took a lot of resilience, persistence and good time management
- Confident understanding of Windows policies, profiles, file and share permissions
- Active Directory admin & maintenance, setting up passwords, groups and creating accounts
- Configuring TCP/IP, DNS and DHCP
- VMware/ VCentre and vSphere client
- Installing / Setting up printers, scanners, iPhones, iPad and other peripherals
- 1st/ 2nd/ 3rd line support
- Server side maintenance checking system and app events, installing and supporting Serco CMIS database
- Cabling computer suites to solve network issues
- Developed a call logger for day to day issues

Floor Manager / Sales Team Supervisor, Cotswold Outdoor May 03* - April 07

- Supervised and motivated an 8 person sales team to meet daily deadlines and hitting monthly sales targets
- Maximise sales and customer service to meet company objectives with good customer service skills noted
- Providing product training and knowledge development to all staff
- Providing direct support to the store management in all aspects of the day to day running of the store including banking, organising staff roster
- Management and organisation of stock maintenance and delivery

*Nov 2003 – Sep 2005 Travelling overseas for 22 months, working in New Zealand for 6 months and Working in Australia for 6 months in temporary sales positions such as a membership consultant for Les Mills Gym, Contact detail gathering for a sale company.

IT Technician, ECI Human Capital Recruitment

March 2000 - May 03

- Maintaining the company's software, hardware and network
- Played an important part in implementing a bespoke recruitment database/ planning solution software (CAPS)
- $1^{st}/2^{nd}$ line support to all recruitment consultants
- Familiarity with all major components of laptops PC's, printer system, including troubleshooting, upgrading and replacement
- Assembling a computer from its basic components, installation of peripheral components, device drivers
- Adding PCs to domain and giving users access to shared drives
- Working knowledge of DOS 6.22, Windows 95/98, NT and Exchange 5.5. and Veritas Backup Exec 9
- Knowledge of installation, configuration, upgrading and removal of hardware components with Windows NT.
- Basic configuration of Lucent Telco Switch.
- MCSE qualified in 2000 MCP included NT Workstation / Sever 4, TCP/IP, Networking Essentials, NT Server 4 in the Enterprise and Exchange 5.5.

Travel Administrator/Air Consultant, Travel Industry Services May 95 – Nov 99

- I Provided direct travel club service to members of the travel industry, client facing and phone sales
- Booking flights, hotels and car hire and finding the right price for our clients
- Collecting outstanding payments
- Dispatching tickets
- Managing customer's queries and complaints

Operation Assistant, GCA Transport Co.

1993 - 1995

- Working with a team of 5 Op. consultants, meeting strict deadlines importing and exporting wine throughout UK and Europe
- Consulting with clients and liaising with container depots for destinations and schedules

EDUCATION

11/99 – 03/2000	MCSE Microsoft Certification	Smart Track Solutions Lee Valley Technopark N17
1991 – 1993	B/TEC National Diploma Business & Finance Pass / Merits	City of Westminster College Saltrum Crescent W11
1990 – 1991	B/TEC First Diploma Business & Finance Merits	City of Westminster College Ladbroke Grove Centre W11
1984 – 1990	8 GCSE's Including Maths & English	Cardinal Manning Boys School St Charles Square W11

Interests & Achievements

- I was part of the Territorial Army (2001 -2003) and for my physical resilience and competitiveness I was put forward to become a Physical Training Instructor (PTI) for the TA
- I set myself a goal of becoming MCSE qualified with no prior knowledge of IT and achieved it in 12 weeks
- My interests in running, cycling and going to the gym keep me positive and self-aware of my capabilities

References

Available on request